{"tossups": [{"question": "Murray Rothbart called this man\u2019s<em> magnum opus</em> the \u201cgreatest work of libertarian philosophy ever written.\u201d Margaret Thatcher\u2019s proclamation that \u201cThere Is No Alternative\u201d derives from this man\u2019s work. This author\u2019s attempts to introduce Lamarckism to sociology were opposed by the American Sociological Association. In a dissent, Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr. proclaimed that \u201cThe 14th Amendment does not enact\u201d this person\u2019s most famous work. For ten points, name this Victorian political theorist and author of<em> Social Statics</em> who coined the term \u201csurvival of the fittest.\u201d", "answer": "Herbert<b> Spencer</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "A cult located on Mount Soracte engaged in practices similar to those practiced on this day. During this celebration, two youths would be taken to an altar to have blood smeared on their foreheads, after which they were expected to laugh. Mark Antony crowned Caesar during this festival in 44 BC. Young men and women were paired off in a fertility lottery during this festival, which landed on February 15th. For ten points, name this ancient Roman pastoral festival whose name derives from the Latin word for\u201cwolf.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Lupercalia</b> (prompt on February 15th before mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "In 2010, Mark Zuckerberg made a $100 million donation to this city\u2019s public school system. For ten points, name this city in New Jersey once led by current Senator Cory Booker.", "answer": "<b> Newark</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This man notes how he \u201cwill miss the battles and the wars\u201d after thanking a man called \u201cCoop\u201d for\u201cstanding side by side.\u201d In that speech, this man appreciated the support of \u201cthe Commissioner, David Stern,\u201d and after affirming that his wife Cookie had \u201cno problem,\u201d he pledged \u201cI plan on going on living for a long time.\u201d Despite giving that retirement speech, this man was later able to play on the 1992 Dream Team with longtime rival Larry Bird. For ten points, name this Los Angeles Laker who, on November 7, 1991, announced his immediate retirement due to HIV.", "answer": "Earvin \u201cMagic\u201d<b> Johnson</b> Jr. Page 1", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "The failed Wagner-Rogers Bill attempted to help 20,000 children during this event. Josiah E. Dubois authored the \u201cReport to the Secretary on the Acquiescence of This Government in\u201d this event, which attacked the State Department\u2019s apathy toward it. The War Refugee Board rescued thousands of victims of this event, though Cuba and the United States refused entry to 900 people fleeing this event aboard the SS<em> Saint Louis</em>. For ten points, name this event that was more or less neglected by FDR\u2019s administration until US troops started liberating concentration camps.", "answer": "The<b> Holocaust</b> (or<b> Shoah</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "After a victory, this commander called his enemy \u201can obstinate old ass bent upon her ruin.\u201d Late in life, this man emancipated the slaves that he had kept at his family home of Traveller\u2019s Rest. An aide to this commander, John Armstrong, authored a letter that was circulated in the Newburgh Conspiracy, and his appointment as President of the Board of War touched off the Conway Cabal. For ten points, name this Revolutionary War general who lost the Battle of Camden but earlier won the Battle of Saratoga.", "answer": "Horatio<b> Gates</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Scott Weidensaul described the \u201cfirst\u201d version of this concept along the Eastern Seaboard. This concept titles a speech that notes \u201cthe problems are not all solved and the battles are not all won,\u201d and claims \u201cwe stand today on the edge of\u201d a \u201cNew\u201d version of this concept. The U.S. Census of 1890 was cited in a paper discussing the \u201cSignificance\u201d of this concept \u201cin American History\u201d by University of Wisconsin historian Frederick Jackson Turner. John F. Kennedy described the 1960s as, for ten points, what idea, the area on the edge of settlement?", "answer": "the American<b> Frontier</b> (accept<b> First Frontier</b>; accept<b> New Frontier</b>; accept<b> Frontier thesis</b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {}, {"question": "This man was suspended without salary for 11 months after a drunken incident in which he nearly hung two sailors who had left their quarters. This man was sent on his most famous voyage with the intent of finding \u201call the totally unknown provinces of Beach.\u201d On one voyage, this man stayed for four weeks in Mauritius until the Roaring Forties allowed him to swiftly sail eastward. He was assisted by a Frans Visscher on a 1642 voyage during which he discovered an island that he named Van Diemen\u2019s Land. For ten points, name this Dutch explorer who discovered New Zealand and an Australian island now named for him.", "answer": "Abel Janszoon<b> Tasman</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was appointed to lead a foreign intervention in the November Uprising after August von Gneisenau died of cholera, though this man later died of cholera, too. This man described a \u201cfascinating trinity\u201d made up of violence, chance, and subordination and, while discussing decision making in the face of uncertain circumstances, coined the term \u201cfog of war.\u201d This man noted that \u201cWar is the continuation of politics by other means\u201d in his most famous work. For ten points, name this 19th century Prussian commander, the author of<em> On War</em>.", "answer": "Carl von<b> Clausewitz</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This island is home to Samaria Gorge National Park, established as a refuge for a population of feral goats known as kri-kri. This island, which was known as Candia while under Venetian rule, was where the Phaistos disc was excavated. This island was home to a Bronze Age civilization that was the target of Arthur Evans\u2019 excavations and which used the still-undeciphered Linear A script. Heraklion is the largest city on, for ten points, what Greek island whose ancient city of Knossos was the center of the Minoan civilization?", "answer": "<b> Crete</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "Mayor William O\u2019Dwyer appointed this man to a \u201ccoordinator\u201d position, from which he developed public authorities to avoid the legislative process. Walter O\u2019Malley\u2019s disagreement with this man over the construction of a new stadium for the Brooklyn Dodgers prompted the team\u2019s move to Los Angeles. This man, who is often erroneously blamed for the demolition of Penn Station, is the subject of Robert Caro\u2019s biography,<em> The Power Broker</em>. For ten points, name this New York city planner notorious for his aversion to public transportation.", "answer": "Robert<b> Moses</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man supported Phocas as Byzantine Emperor over Maurice, who had been emperor while this man was serving as apocrisiarius. He built the Monastery of Saint Andrew on the Caelian Hill, which his family owned. This man cultivated peace with Agilulf by meeting with his wife, Theodelinda, Queen of Lombardy, and he dispatched Augustine of Canterbury to convert the British Isles. For ten points, name this 6th century pope who laid the foundation for the medieval papacy and whose love for music inspired a series of namesake chants for use in monasteries.", "answer": "Pope Saint<b> Gregory the Great</b> (or<b> Gregory I</b>; accept<b> Gregorian</b> chant after \u201cchant\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The founder of this kingdom belonged to the Banu al-Ahmar clan in Arjona. This kingdom supported a failed invasion by the Marinid dynasty, which was defeated at the Battle of R\u00b4\u0131o Salado. This kingdom was able to unite the remaining independent cities after defeat at the Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa. A ruler of this kingdom was, after its fall, given an estate in the Alpujarras; that man, Boabdil, ruled from the Alhambra palace. For ten points, name this last Muslim kingdom in Iberia that was conquered by Ferdinand and Isabella in 1492.", "answer": "Sultanate of<b> Granada</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Archaeological sites built by this civilization contain E-group buildings that were probably used as astronomical observatories. Temples built by this civilization may have been rebuilt every fifty two years, corresponding to the cycles of their Long Count calendar. A temple built by this civilization displays the shadow of a snake crawling up a pyramid every equinox; that building is the Temple of Kukulcan. For ten points, name this civilization that constructed the cities of Tikal and Chichen Itza.", "answer": "<b> Maya</b>n Civilization", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This composer\u2019s</b><em><b> The Combat of Tancredi and Clorinda</b></em><b>, which contains one of the earliest uses of pizzicato, was published in his eighth book of madrigals. He coined the term\u201cseconda practica\u201d to differentiate his music from the older style of (+) Palestrina. One of his operas depicts the ascent of Nero\u2019s second wife, while his first opera depicts a legendary (*)</b> musician who travels to the underworld to rescue Eurydice. For ten points,<em> The Coronation of Poppea</em> and<em> L\u2019Orfeo</em> were written by what Italian composer who pioneered the Baroque style of music?", "answer": "Claudio<b> Monteverdi</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>Daniel Webster called this document \u201cpractically prejudicial\u201d in an attempt to rescind it. \u201cNineteen twentieths of the whole people approve[d]\u201d of this order, according to the</b> <b>president who signed it on July 11, 1836. Secretary of the (+)</b> <b>Treasury Levi Woodbury</b> <b>issued this order, which temporarily allowed for up to 320 acres of settled land to be paid in (*) </b> banknotes, but required everything else to be paid through gold and silver coinage. For ten points, name this anti-speculation executive order of Andrew Jackson that contributed to the Panic of 1837.", "answer": "<b> Specie Circular</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>At this battle, one side knelt in prayer in full view of enemy lines after a favorable spy report from Alexander Seton enticed them to attack. The Earl of Hereford\u2019s nephew Henry</b> <b>de Bohun was beheaded in single combat at this battle. The Treaty of (+)</b> <b>Edinburgh-</b> <b>Northampton was signed after this battle, fulfilling the goals of the prior Declaration of Arbroath. During this battle, Edward II\u2019s attempts to relieve (*)</b> Stirling Castle were thwarted by the schiltrons of the successor of William Wallace. For ten points, name this 1314 battle, a victory for Robert the Bruce of Scotland.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Bannockburn</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man ceded land to his eastern neighbor and promised to punish some assassins in the Treaty of Arras. Those assassins had killed his rival, John the Fearless, while this man was negotiating with him to end a conflict between the Armagnacs and Burgundians. The Treaty of Troyes, signed shortly after the Battle of (+) Agincourt, tried to block this \u201cKing of Bourges\u201d from the throne. Shortly after recapturing Tourelles, this man\u2019s army was able to (*)</b> lift the Siege of Orleans. For ten points, name this French king who won the Hundred Years\u2019 War and was crowned by Joan of Arc at Reims Cathedral.", "answer": "<b> Charles VII</b> of France (accept<b> Charles the Victorious</b> or<b> Charles le Victorieux</b>; accept <b>Charles the Well-Served</b> or<b> Charles le Bien-Servi</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>During this event, one man was labeled \u201cOle Hanson of the East.\u201d In the prelude to this event, Andrew Peters stated \u201cthe whole situation is far more serious than I realized.\u201d After</b> <b>this event, formerly unemployed (+)</b> <b>World War I veterans were refused new uniforms by</b> <b>the Garment Workers\u2019 Union. Samuel Gompers supported the perpetrators of this event and blamed Commissioner (*) </b> Edwin Upton Curtis for causing it by refusing to recognize a new union. For ten points, name this 1919 strike, quashed in a profile-raising performance by Massachusetts Governor Calvin Coolidge.", "answer": "1919<b> Boston police strike</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This type of force first saw combat during the capture of Masnedo fortress in Operation Weserubung. These forces became less prominent after a high rate of casualties suffered during Operation Mercury, an attack on Crete. During the Normandy invasion, (+) Rommel asparagus was used to hinder these troops, who served as pathfinders. Otto Skorzeny executed the Gran Sasso raid to rescue Benito Mussolini using these units, known as (*)</b> \u201cfallschirmjagers\u201d [fall-shirm-yea-gers]. For ten points, name these infantry units, including the 101st \u201cScreaming Eagles,\u201d who jumped during D-Day.", "answer": "<b> paratrooper</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>An engraving of this painting is in the background of John Everett Millais\u2019</b><em><b> The Black </b><b>Brunswicker</b></em><b>. The subject of this painting refused to sit for this work, claiming that \u201cgreat</b> <b>men of (+)</b> <b>Antiquity\u201d would not have done so. Its artist signed this work with his name</b> <b>followed by \u201cYear Nine,\u201d a reference to its start date in 1801. This work depicts a scene in the Great (*)</b> St. Bernard Pass in which a commander rears a horse and points heroically upward. For ten points, name this Jacques-Louis David showing a French commander traversing a European mountain range.", "answer": "<b> Napoleon Crossing the Alps</b> (accept<b> Napoleon at the Saint-Bernard Pass</b>; accept", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>An 1890 law review article co-written by Samuel Warren and Louis Brandeis about this right examined the case of</b><em><b> Prince Albert v. Strange</b></em><b> to argue for its existence in America. Tort law commonly gives four separate causes of action for violations of this right, which</b> <b>include (+)</b> <b>\u201cfalse light\u201d and appropriation. The \u201cpenumbras\u201d of various amendments</b> <b>\u201cfalse light\u201d and appropriation. The \u201cpenumbras\u201d of various amendments</b> <b>provided this right according to Douglas\u2019s majority opinion in (*)</b> <b>provided this right according to Douglas\u2019s majority opinion in (*)</b> <em>Griswold v. Connecticut</em>, which first recognized this right in the Constitution. For ten points, name this concept that was used by the Court to defend a woman\u2019s right to an abortion in<em> Roe v. Wade</em>.", "answer": "right to<b> privacy</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A collection of artifacts from this dynasty was discovered after an Arab</b><em><b> dhow</b></em><b> carrying its namesake \u201ctreasure\u201d shipwrecked off the coast of Belitung. Li Jiancheng was assassinated</b> <b>in a coup during this dynasty called the (+)</b> <b>Xuanwu [shu-an-wu] Gate Incident. During</b> <b>this dynasty, a member of the Four Beauties, Yang Guifei, adopted a famous rebel whose insurrection led to possibly over 30 million deaths. (*) </b> Du Fu and Li Po were poets during, for ten points, what Chinese dynasty that succeeded the Sui Dynasty and experienced the An Lushan Rebellion?", "answer": "<b> Tang</b> Dynasty ", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Defenders of this island were massacred after the capture of Fort St. Elmo. Charles</b> <b>I received a falcon in exchange for this island from an organization that had been</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>evicted from Rhodes and Cyprus; they stayed on this island until the reign of</b> <b>Napoleon. An Ottoman invasion of this island was defeated by Grand Master (*)</b> Jean de la Valette, who now names this island\u2019s capital. For ten points, name this Mediterranean island once owned by the Knights Hospitallers.", "answer": "<b> Malta</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}